Today we are here to do the Guru's puja
今日はグルプージャをします
The Guru is praised more than the Deities and the Gods
グルは神々よりも称賛されます
Who is this Guru?
グルとはいかなる存在でしょう
In this, which is the most important shakti?
グルに最も大切な力は何でしょう
The Guru tattwa is the Shiva.
シヴァこそがグルの原理です
The form of the Shiva's power we should consider as the Guru's power.
シヴァの力の現れが グルの力であると見なせます
Because when we take the powers from the Guru's shakti,
グルの力を授かったり
and when the shaktis come within us then we ourselves become the Guru
グルになって力を得ると
And with this, we are blessed for the whole life (Kalyan).
一生の祝福を授かります
The one who gets these powers,
この力を得た者は
it seems he has got all the blessings (kalyan).
全ての祝福を授かったように見えます
"Kalyan" is a word which is very hard to explain in a few words.
カッリャンという言葉は 簡潔に説明するのがとても難しい言葉ですが
"Kalyan" means to get blessed from all the sides.
カッリャンとはあらゆる方角から祝福を授かる
When someone says that in the blessings you have got the Kalyan,
誰かがカッリャンを得たといったら
what does it mean?
どのような意味になるでしょう
What is Kalyan?
カッリャンとは何でしょう
Kalyan means Atma Sakshatkar, the Self-Realisation.
それはアトマ（自己）の現れであり セルフリアリゼーションのことです
Without the Self-Realisation, you cannot have the Kalyan.
セルフリアリゼーションなしに カッリャンはあり得ません
Nobody can understand without having it.
それなしに理解することはできません
All these things are in the Kalyan.
カッリャンにこれら全てが 含まれています
Because of this a person gets all the joy, and he becomes radiant.
あらゆる歓びを得て 彼は輝きを放ちます
To have this Kalyan, whatever you have to do you have done it all,
このカッリャンのために 全てのことをしてきたし
whatever efforts you have to make it has all been made,
あなたの全ての努力や
the faith which you have to take, you have already taken it.
全ての信仰がカッリャンのためだったのです
But when you are all in the "Kalyanmarg" (Path of Kalyan),
でもあなたがカッリャンへの道中にある時
when he has given the mantra to have the Kalyan,
カッリャンへのマントラを与えられたとしたら
It means that the most important thing
それにはどんな意味があるのでしょう
Afterwards you all don't have to search for anything,
すると探求することはなくなり
you have all become the Gurus.
自分がグルになるのです
You don't have to take some great things in this moment,
もはや大切な何かを 得ようとする必要もありません
but the blessings of this samadhana
このサマダンの恩恵は
you all can know inside yourselves
誰でも自身の内面で感じられ
you all can enjoy within yourselves.
知ることができ
First of all you all can see that the physical diseases,
まず身体の病気に気づきます
the physical problems can be removed by this Kalyanmarg,
身体の問題がカッリャンの道中でなくなります
all the problems which are coming within you
あなたが開花するのを妨げるような
that prevent you from blossoming,
内面の全ての問題が
can be removed by this Kalyanmarg.
カッリャンへの道中で取り除かれるでしょう
When you all take to this, you get the Kalyan
これにより誰であれカッリャンを得て
In this Shri Mahadeva is helping you.
ここではシュリマハデーヴァが助けています
When the kundalini opens the sahasrara,
クンダリニによりサハスララが開く時
Shri Mahadeva is sitting over there.
その上にシュリマハデーヴァが座しています
And because of this, we call Him Mahadeva.
この意味で彼はマハデーヴァと呼ばれます
It means the God of all the Gods, Mahadeva.
マハデーヴァとは神々の神という意味です
in this Kalyan there are many important aspects.
カッリャンには多くの重要な面があります
The first thing is shanti (peace).
まずはシャンティ（平穏）です
Mental peace, physical peace and the peace in the family life.
心身や家庭の平穏です
In the family life there are many problems, many obstacles,
家庭生活には沢山の問題や障害がありますが
and all these can be solved by the Kalyanmarg.
すべてカッリャンへの努力により解決されます
In this way we could see many people in the whole world
世界中の多くの人々が
getting blessings from this Kalyanmarg and meditating upon it
カッリャンを得ようと瞑想し
and enjoying for the whole life.
人生をまるごと楽しんでいます
This is the Kalyan by which mankind
このカッリャンにより人類は
can get the balances within themselves.
内的バランスを得るのです
And to obtain this balance,
そのバランスのためには
you have to go under the protection of the Guru.
グルの守りが必要です
When you become the devotee of a Guru,
グルの信奉者になると
you get the balance and you get everything.
このバランスと他の全てを手に入れます
After this you do not need anything.
この後で必要なものはありません
In this way we get the balance
こうしてバランスを得て
and we obtain the power of love within ourselves.
自分の中に愛の力を獲得します
When mankind obtains this, this whole body rejoices.
人がそれを得ると　全身が歓びに沸き立ちます
When you obtain this state,
この意識を得ると
the shaktis (powers) destroy all the problems,
シャクティの力が全ての問題を破壊して
the disturbances in the body and the physical state,
身体的にも物質的にも 障害がなくなります
and so many people try very hard to obtain this shakti.
なので多くの人が この力を得ようと努力しているのです
He can get the shakti only form a person that is self-realised.
でもこれは自己を悟った人からだけ 授かることが可能で
and then he himself becomes in the God's form.
それを授かると終には彼自身が 神のようになっていきます
This is a subject which you can only explain in Hindi language,
これはヒンディー語でないと説明できない現象で
which says that this Guru Padh you get from somebody else.
グルの資格というのは誰か他者により 与えられるものだけれども
But that somebody else is itself, is endowed with, the power
その誰かはそれに足る力を持っている 必要があるということです
the power of peace of mind, to begin with,
まずはこころの平穏
and also the power to overcome all kinds of of earthly problems,
次にあらゆる俗世の問題を 克服する力
mental problems, physical problems.
そして心身の問題を克服する力です
All these problems you can solve through your mental balance
全ての問題を グルから授かる 精神のバランスと祝福で克服できます
When you become the Guru,
あなたがグルになると あなたが人を祝福する力を得ます
With your blessing power you can create a guru out of many.
あなたの祝福の力で多くの者がグルになります
And once the Guru is created and there is a Guru,
そしてそのような力を持った グルが生まれることは
who has this power, it's very satisfying and is very [UNCLEAR: enabling?].
とても満たされることです
The satisfaction is so much that you don't want anything.
それ以外何も望まないほどの満足です
This is the power of Shiva.
これがシヴァの力です
You have seen Shiva, doesn't have much clothes,
シヴァはご存じの通りあまり服を着ていません
He doesn't decorate Himself,
自分を飾りません
He is just sitting in meditative mood, all the time.
常に瞑想的な雰囲気で座っています
He doesn't want anything.
何も求めません
He's so satisfied with Himself that He doesn't want anything.
大変満足していて何も求めません
And that is the power you get after the Self-realization,
自己を悟るとあなたはこの力を得るのです
if you have a Guru, and Guru of that level and caliber.
あなたにそれに足るのグルがいればです
One should not try to become a Guru.
自分からグルになろうとしないことです
That's very, impractical.
現実的ではありません
If you try to become, you'll never.
なろうとするとなれません
It has to come to you automatically,
求めることも努力もせずに 向こうから自然にやってくるものです
So the only way you can get to it is through Dhyana.
唯一の方法はディヤーナです
Dhyana is meditation.
ディヤーナとは瞑想です
When you meditate,
瞑想する際
just meditate, and meditate, do not ask for anything.
何も求めずただ瞑想しなさい
Meditation itself gives you
瞑想自体があなたに
that instrument which can bear this great power of the Guru.
グルの偉大な力に足る道具を与えます
And then you automatically, you give this power to others;
すると自然にあなたは他者に力を与えます
you don't have to work it out.
あなたがしなくても良いのです
Just in your presence,
あなたがいるだけで
people can get this power .
人々がこの力を得ます
of complete satisfaction
完全な満足です
And there is salvation, for you and for others.
そこには自他の解放があります
So all the problems which are faced
上昇の旅における問題は 全て無くなり
and you [are or now] drenched in the bliss of heavenly
あなたは天上の平和と歓びの 至福に満たされます
That's why it is called as Kaivalya,
なのでこれは祝福そのものという意味の カイヴァラヤと呼ばれます
See that means there is no other word to translate it.
他の言葉に訳せません
There's no other way of explaining it.
他に説明する術もありません
It's a state. It's a Stithi.
ある意識状態　スティティです
It's a state, in that state you have to rise
その状態に上って行きなさい
and you know that you are in that state.
そこにいる自覚がありますね
It's a very remarkable thing,
それは真に偉大なことで
that once you reach that state you don't have to ask for anything.
到達したらもう何も求める必要が無く
It's all there, and you are so satisfied.
全てがあり満たされています
I can go on talking about this special power
この特別な力についていくらでもお話しできますが
but I think whatever I have said please meditate on that.
私の話したことについて ぜひ瞑想してください
And you are all capable of reaching that state.
皆がそこに至れる力があります
That state of complete peace and joy.
この完全なる平穏と歓びの状態に
May God bless you.
神の祝福を